preen.me 2019-05-14

# Privacy Policy | Preen.Me

Please note that by using Preen.Me and related websites (the “Site”) or the services (the “Services”) provided by Crowdsmiths Inc. (“Crowdsmiths”, “Preen.Me” “we” or “us”) or third-party survey tools, landing pages and the like controlled by Preen.Me (the “Tools”) you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site or Services.   
We also may collect publicly available information associated with publicly avilible information on social media and the internet. This pooled information, or ‘personal data’, is made available as part of our market-research and Influencer relationship Services to help our client receive statistical and research information and also build, manage, expand their relationships with influencers.   
This Privacy Policy is part of and is governed by, the terms and conditions set forth in our Terms of Use. 

**How to contact us?**  
We are committed to answering inquiries about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. If you have an inquiry or complaint regarding this privacy policy, please contact us at [info@preen.me](mailto:info@preen.me).  
You can also mail us at: Crowdsmiths Inc., 340 S Lemon Ave #2527 Walnut, CA 91789 USA 

**What is the purpose of this Privacy Policy?**  
This Privacy Policy discloses our personal information gathering and dissemination practices with respect to the Site, Services, and Tools. We have also created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our commitment to privacy   
By using the Service or submitting personal information through the Service, you expressly consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information according to this Privacy Policy. 

**What information do we collect from users and how is it used?**  
The following describes the types of personal and other information we may collect about you, and how we use and maintain that information:   
Information collected online can generally be categorized as either non-personal information or personally identifiable information. Non-personal information is information that cannot by itself be traced back to a specific individual. Personally identifiable information is information you provide to us that is uniquely associated with you, such as your name, social media account or email address.   
We process the personal information we obtain on our servers in the United States of America and in other countries. In some cases, we process personal information on a server outside your own country. Laws regarding processing personal information may be less stringent than the laws in your country.   
Although we currently do not have a parent company, we do have subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, "Affiliates"), and we may in the future have more such relationships. We may share some or all of your personal information with these Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.In the event, we go through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets to which this Privacy Policy relates, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur. 

**Registration**  
Before you can utilize certain Services that we offer on the Site or otherwise, we may ask that you register with us and provide us with your email address, social accounts, a password, your first and last name and other contact information and personal details. We request this information for identification purposes, to communicate with you regarding your account, and to facilitate the functioning of certain Services. We may keep this information indefinitely.Correspondence & Usage DataIf you correspond with us via email, chat, social media, survey, questions and responses and any other means we may gather in a file specific to you the information that you submit. We may keep this information indefinitely.   
We may also collect information indirectly or passively when interacting with us, such as: 

a) Usage data: we collect usage data about Users whenever they interact with our services, including information they have elected to make publicly available. 

b) Information from third parties: we may collect personal information or data from third parties if the User gives permission to those third parties to share such information with others or the data is extracted from publicly accessible sources. 

We may also collect your personal information or data if you submit it to us in other contexts. For example, if you provide us with a testimonial, reviews, content entries to our various programs.   
URL and IP addressLike many other services, we collect information about users’ utilization and navigation of our Tools, Site and use of Services. This information helps us to design our Site and Services to better suit our users’ needs. For example, our Site or Services will track the URL that you visited before you came to our Site or used our Services, the URL to which you next go, your Internet Protocol (IP) address and any URLs to which you link using the Services. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Site or Services. Your IP address also is used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. 

**Social media account information**  
When you share with us your social account or register using a social media account we may collect avilible information associated with the social account and that is provided by the social media network, such as name, age, statistical follower count, public bio information and public posts. We may keep this information indefinitely. You may limit the information shared via your social account by editing or configuring your social media account cordially.Information Collected With CookiesLike most major websites and services, we may use cookies on certain pages of our Site or pages using our Services. Cookies make using the Internet easier by, among other things, saving your preferences for you. For example, a cookie lets a Site, Tools or Services remember that you’ve registered, which allows us to speed up your future activities at our Tools, Site or Services, and which allows you to enter your registration information less frequently while visiting our Tools, Site or using our Services. We may also use cookies to deliver content tailored to your interests. Our cookies may enable us to relate your use of our Tools, Site or Services to personally identifying information that you previously submitted, such as calling you by name when you return to our Tools, Site or use our Services. If your browser is set to reject cookies, or if your browser notifies you that you are about to receive a cookie and you reject it, then your use of the Site or Services may not be as efficient or as enjoyable as it would be if the cookie were enabled. The information that we collect with cookies allows us to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze Site or Services usage, to improve our content and product offerings and to customize our Site’s or Services’ content, or layout. However, we only use information collected with cookies on an aggregated basis without the use of any information that personally identifies you. You may opt out of our use of cookies by configuring your browser to reject them. 

**Market Research and Influencer Database**  
As part of our Services, we have developed and manage a market-research and Influencer relationship infrastructure which helps our client receive statistical and research information and also to build, manage, expand their relationships with influencers.   
As such we may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of publicly available personal data about you which is obtained indirectly via secondary sources such as social media networks and other Internet sources. This personal data may include the following: your social media handle, follower and following count, your name, age, affiliated organization, social posts or messages or bio information which you have shared publicly on social media.   
As part of activities with Influencers, we facilitate the connection between companies, their brands and influencers to tap into their subject-matter expertise. We provide a mutual benefit to both brands and influencers by empowering them to build meaningful relationships for their shared gain.   
Additionally, we provide a greater public benefit by providing insight into the power of user-generated content on the overall economic ecosystem.   
You can ask us to stop processing your personal data. To do this, please email us with your details and social accounts at [info@preen.me](mailto:info@preen.me)

 **To whom do we disclose information about you that we collect?**  
We may share your personal data with the persons and in the contexts set out below: 

\- We may disclose information that we collect about you to our third-party contractors or partners who perform services for us in order to provide certain services or to complete or confirm a transaction that you conduct with us.- We may disclose the results of aggregated data about you for research, marketing or promotional purposes. 

\- We may disclose publicly avilible information you have made avilible on your social media account for marketing or promotional purposes or if we believe you are a possible candidate for a future Preen.Me or client program. 

\- When you use a co-branded service within our network of tools, sites or users, you grant us permission to pass your registration information back to that partner. Their use of your information is subject to their applicable privacy policies. 

\- When you show interest or participate in a co-branded program such as challenge, giveaway, content creation activity, you grant us permission to pass your registration and public information back to that partner. Their use of your information is subject to their applicable privacy policies. 

\- We may disclose information about you as part of a merger, acquisition or other sale or transfer of its assets or business. We do not guarantee that any entity receiving such information in connection with one of these transactions will comply with all terms of this Privacy Policy.- We may be legally obligated to preserve or disclose information about you to the government or to third parties under certain circumstances, such as in connection with illegal activity on our Site or Services or to respond to a subpoena, court order or other legal processes. we reserve the right to preserve or disclose information that we collect to law enforcement or other government officials, as we, in our sole and absolute discretion, deem necessary or appropriate. 

\- We may disclose third parties with whom we may be required to communicate in order to enforce or apply the terms of our agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or our safety, our customers, or others. 

**What security measures do we employ?**  
We take steps to protect the user data we collect against unauthorized access. However, you should keep in mind that out Tools, Site, and our Services are run on software, hardware and networks, any component of which may, from time to time, require maintenance or experience problems or breaches of security beyond our control.   
We take commercially reasonable security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of information that you share and that we store.   
We restrict access to personal information only to our employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Tools, Site or Services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution if they fail to meet these obligations. However, no security system can be fully secured; accordingly, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you provide to us in connection with the delivery of our Services.   
Please also be aware that despite our best intentions and the guidelines outlined in this Privacy Policy, no data transmission over the Internet or encryption method can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. 

**How can you access, correct or update information that we collect about you?**  
You may access, review, correct, update, change or delete your information at any time. To do so, please contact us at [info@preen.me](mailto:info@preen.me) with your name, social accounts and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed.   
We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, would be extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case, where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. We may retain your information as necessary to support the Services, comply with our legal obligations or resolve disputes.   
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your Personal Data.. This is a security measure to ensure that Personal Data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.   
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

**What are the policies of linked sites and other third parties?**  
This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. You should be aware that when you are on the Site or using the Services, you can be directed to other websites that are beyond our control, and we is not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties or the content of linked websites. We encourage you to read the posted privacy policy whenever interacting with any website. 

**What is our policy on children’s data?**  
We do not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information from persons under 13 years old, and no part of our Site is directed to persons under 13. IF YOU ARE UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE, PLEASE DO NOT USE OR ACCESS OUR SITE AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER.   
If we learn that personally identifiable information of persons less than 13 years old has been collected, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has their data with us, then you may alert us at info@preen.me and request that we delete that child’s personal information from our systems.   
**  
Legitimate Interests.**  
We may use your personal information for our legitimate interests to provide our products, our partners’ products, and our Services and to improve our Services. We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which it was obtained unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us by emailing info@preen.me.If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will update this privacy notice and explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law. 

**Data Retention.**  
We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was obtained. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. 

**Changes in the Privacy Policy**  
We reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please visit this page periodically so that you will be apprised of any changes. 

Effective as of May 25, 2018
